hello and welcome to the 19 tutorial on
how to program in gript 2 so in this
tutorial I'm going to go over a very
important Concept in uscript
2 and that's an
array an array is really just a big
group of variables like any normal
variable so for example um let's do this
I'm going to use the onall weapon before
because I already have it added to
myself so let me add this
you can name it whatever you want I'm
going to just name it
array I'm just going to name it array
then let's add these little brackets no
these
brackets and
add a bunch of values for the array so
let's add one comma one comma one comma
one no let's add one comma 2 comma 3
comma four comma
5 okay and then we just end that array
and that's an array it's made five
different
variables and the first one is one
second one is two second one third one
is three fourth one is four and fifth
one is
five now if we want to call them this is
what we do we go here and add let's add
player. chat is equal
to this.
array and then these brackets and
whatever value we want so let's
put
zero now here's where it gets kind of
confusing whatever value put in here is
going to be like here but minus one so
if we put in zero it would be the first
value even if this is the first value
it's not the zeroth value but zero is
the first one if we put one it'd be the
second one if we put two it'd be the
third variable if we put three it'd be
the fourth variable and so on so let's
add
zero so when when
I so whenever I say something like hi
it's going to say
one now we have five variables
here what we can do is change them so
let's add this this do
array 0 is equal to 10
this will change the first value to
10 so when I say hi I'm going to say
10 now there's another way to call well
there's some more ways to call arrays
and this is another set
array the name of the array
um array I'm just going to name it array
again comma How many array
variables we want so let's put 100
variables then end that I'm pretty sure
this is gript one but I'm not sure how
to just make a giant group of arrays in
gript
2 other than you know this. array equal
to one and
just repeating this over and over and
over and over again until it gets to
like a
100 but yeah I'm going to be doing this
cuz I'm not sure how and no resource has
been able to tell me I'm not even sure
if there is a
way now there is no this is not really a
type of variable it's just array like
there's no there's no prefix to the type
of variable so this is actually a global
varial and it'll work for all the other
weapons but we're just going to use it
in this one let's
add all of them are currently equal to
nothing by the way way let's add
array 10 is equal
to um five or something now let's here
add oops player. chat is equal to array
10 if I want to say hi I'm going to say
five anyway that concludes this tutorial
um I hope you have a better
understanding on arrays
and we'll be going we'll be making
something with them in next tutorial so
anyway um bye